Gather round, come take a look...
It's time for Theatre of Darkness
The End of Death
This is a story concerning a custom in a certain village...
It was called Worth Dying For.
Shinigai = Worth Dying For
Those who picked a toy car would die in an accident;
those who picked a stone, in a disaster;
those who picked medicine, from illness;
those who picked a rope, by suicide;
and those who picked a hatchet would be murdered.
When a child first starts walking,
they are made to walk from the edge of the room.
The number of steps and the item chosen,
determine the age and manner of their death.
I walked 27 steps
and chose the hatchet.
Listen up Koichi,
you live fast and die young, got it?
Our Koichi,
will be murdered and die at age 27,
so everyone please be nice to him, okay?
Okay!
I thought they were out of their minds,
but to them, this was normal.
Grandpa, it’s almost time for you to die.
I wonder how it's going to be...
Because the time until death was set,
they believed one could fulfill their life
without regrets.
The villagers truly believed that.
But me,
those people are deeply creepy from the bottom of my heart.
It didn't take me long to decide to run away from home.
Don't look for me
By Kouchi
Nine years since then.
Once midnight strikes,
I'll turn 27.
What a joke!
"Shinigai" my ass!
W-Who is it?
Your Mother.
Mother?
I wanted to see you before you die.
Open the door.
S-Shut up!
Get lost!
Koichi,
it's me.
You shouldn't be alone on a day like this,
with your family...
I won't be fooled!
You're just saying that to try and kill me!
Calm down...
Koichi!
Open the door Koichi!
Shut up! Get lost!
I decide my own destiny!
I decide my...
Is it morning already...?
This is the police.
Yes.
You are Koichi Yoshimura, right?
There's something we'd like to ask you—
It's about all those villagers being murdered, right?
I did it three days ago.
I thought I'd kill them all before they could kill me.
Ah, the murder weapon is right there.
They're incredible, those guys.
Even though they were already dead last night,
they still came to kill me.
Let's hear the details at the station...
Sure thing.
I feel great right now.
I finally feel like,
I've grabbed hold of my own life.
The End
This episode parodies Erabitori (選取り), a traditional Japanese First Birthday custom where a baby picks an object to predict their future career or traits.
In this village's twisted version, called Shinigai (死に甲斐 - "Worth Dying For"), the chosen object predicts their cause of death, while the number of steps dictates their lifespan.
Driven by paranoia as his predicted death day approached, Koichi massacred his whole village three days prior to "take control of his destiny," only to realize the villagers' vengeful spirits still came to fulfill the prophecy.
Gather round, come take a look...
It's time for Theatre of Darkness
It's time for Theatre of Darkness...?